{"test_questions": [[{"question": "3, 5, 11, 14, 17, 21", "opta": "21", "optb": "17", "optc": "14", "optd": "3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Each of the numbers except 14 is an odd number.\nThe number '14' is the only EVEN number."}, {"question": "8, 27, 64, 100, 125, 216, 343", "opta": "27", "optb": "100", "optc": "125", "optd": "343", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The pattern is 23, 33, 43, 53, 63, 73. But, 100 is not a perfect cube."}, {"question": "10, 25, 45, 54, 60, 75, 80", "opta": "10", "optb": "45", "optc": "54", "optd": "75", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Each of the numbers except 54 is multiple of 5."}, {"question": "396, 462, 572, 427, 671, 264", "opta": "396", "optb": "427", "optc": "671", "optd": "264", "ans": "B", "explanation": "In each number except 427, the middle digit is the sum of other two."}, {"question": "6, 9, 15, 21, 24, 28, 30", "opta": "28", "optb": "21", "optc": "24", "optd": "30", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Each of the numbers except 28, is a multiple of 3."}, {"question": "1, 4, 9, 16, 23, 25, 36", "opta": "9", "optb": "23", "optc": "25", "optd": "36", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Each of the numbers except 23, is perfect square."}, {"question": "1, 4, 9, 16, 20, 36, 49", "opta": "1", "optb": "9", "optc": "20", "optd": "49", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The pattern is 12, 22, 32, 42, 52, 62, 72. But, instead of 52, it is 20 which to be turned out."}, {"question": "2, 5, 10, 17, 26, 37, 50, 64", "opta": "50", "optb": "26", "optc": "37", "optd": "64", "ans": "D", "explanation": "(1*1)+1 , (2*2)+1 , (3*3)+1 , (4*4)+1 , (5*5)+1 , (6*6)+1 , (7*7)+1 , (8*8)+1\nBut, 64 is out of pattern."}, {"question": "10, 14, 16, 18, 21, 24, 26", "opta": "26", "optb": "24", "optc": "21", "optd": "18", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Each of the numbers except 21 is an even number."}, {"question": "16, 25, 36, 72, 144, 196, 225", "opta": "36", "optb": "72", "optc": "196", "optd": "225", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Each of the numbers except 72 is a perfect square."}, {"question": "331, 482, 551, 263, 383, 362, 284", "opta": "263", "optb": "383", "optc": "331", "optd": "551", "ans": "B", "explanation": "In each number except 383, the product of first and third digits is the middle one."}, {"question": "835, 734, 642, 751, 853, 981, 532", "opta": "751", "optb": "853", "optc": "981", "optd": "532", "ans": "A", "explanation": "In each number except 751, the difference of third and first digit is the middle one."}, {"question": "41, 43, 47, 53, 61, 71, 73, 81", "opta": "61", "optb": "71", "optc": "73", "optd": "81", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Each of the numbers except 81 is a prime number."}, {"question": "3, 5, 7, 12, 17, 19", "opta": "19", "optb": "17", "optc": "5", "optd": "12", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Each of the numbers is a prime number except 12."}]]}